Over the last decade,
I've grown my fitness brand to be over
four million followers.
We've done eight figures in revenue.
I started from doing face-to-face sessions
for about £25 an hour.
I've scaled it to doing seven figures a
year.
If I had to lose everything
and start again overnight, this video,
I'm going to
explain exactly how I'd do it.
The thing is,
it would definitely be different
starting over again because the landscape
is so different to when I began, and the
businesses that I'm working with at the
moment are having to face a completely
different set of challenges to the ones
that I had to face back then.
The reality is as well,
you're just going to need five steps to do
this.
Now,
in case you've never seen any of my stuff
before, my name's James Smith, and
on top of running a fitness business,
sold over a million books, run a $20
million nootropic and drinks brand.
Yeah,
three times number one bestselling author,
a few million on social media,
something like that.
Whereas a lot of my competitors have only
done one thing and
been hyper successful in it,
I kind of have a recipe
that I keep repeating in
different avenues, and shit works.
So if we look into the first step,
I would call it to niche or not to niche.
And to answer that question properly,
let's start with the first question.
What do we make content about? Well,
firstly, not your lunch, not the
workout that you did. There
are so many personal trainers,
perhaps yourself, you
wake up, you go, "Cool. Hey, guys.
Here's my workout of the day." No one
cares.
No one woke up today going, "God,
wish I could just follow someone's
workout." No
one woke up today going, "Oh,
I just wish I could see someone's lunch."
The real
reality is,
I know it's a bit early to say this,
no one gives a fuck about you.
You don't even give a fuck about me,
and that's fine.
What you give a fuck about
is the knowledge that I have
and the things that I can
give you over the next few minutes
that are going to revolutionize
and change your
business.
You're bought into how I can help you,
and your clients are bought into
how you can help them.
So what do you make content about?
Here's a start.
Write down five problems
that your clients have.
Now, those problems
are probably going to come from clients
you work with
face-to-face. Now,
you might have deaf ears to this, but
when you're working with
your client, they're between sets,
they go,
"Are macros important?" You give them a
fucking TED Talk on macros like, "Yeah,
about carbs, fats, or protein as a
constant variable."
And then you talk about different
intensities and heart rates
and fat burning zones and all of that.
Then you get home, you go,
"I don't know what to make content about."
If your
client ever asks you a question,
it's a goldmine.
It's the reason I'm so active in the
Discord with people in my business
mentorship.
Yeah, I want to help them. Yeah,
I want to scale their businesses.
Yeah,
I want them to be financially free
and look after their family.
But more important than that,
I want to have a finger on the pulse of
all the
problems that they're dealing with so I
can make it a video
and make loads of money
from it. But remember, obviously,
do want to help them, but mostly me.
Just like you.
You want to help your clients,
you want to help them get in shape,
you want to help them lose weight
and all that,
but really wouldn't be bad to fly
business class, would it? And
if you're not flying business already,
that's
fine-ish. Obesity epidemic,
people dying from overeating more than
undereating. But anyway,
we'll get back into that.
So all the content you make,
there's a bit of tongue in cheek here.
I'm English.
This is what we do. Being British,
we ain't got the best genetics.
We got to make up for it with chat.
So all the content you make
is going to revolve
around problems. For instance,
I've noted a problem within the fitness
industry
that a lot of people are panicking
and don't know how to start 2026.
They don't know how they should start a
fitness brand, and there are a lot of
complexities and nuances to that.
So I make this video.
I'm just here solving problems for you
because I know if 1,000 of you
are watching
this and I solve 100 of them to the point
that you're like, "Is this guy reading my
mind?" Two or three of you
are end up going to click a link in the
description and
you're going to give me your money,
which is great for me.
So you're like, "Cool, yeah,
everyone online is saying it needs to be
content about
people's problems.
How do I stand out?" Okay.
First of all, you can make content
but better.
Someone might explain something,
you might explain it with a story, with an
analogy.
You also just might put more care
and attention into how that video
is made. For instance,
there's a lot of people on YouTube making
these kinds of
videos.
Have many of them built a $70,000 studio
with a
$10,000 camera setup? Everything here,
the silence, the cuts, the
edits, the lighting,
is all about delivering this to you in the
best way possible.
I don't ramble. I do a bit. But this
is succinct.
I'm going to hopefully pretty much make it
entertaining so you can have a bit of a
giggle on the way.
So you've got several ways to be better
than your competition.
One, make the video better.
Add a bit of humor.
Make it easier to understand using
analogies, similes, metaphors,
whatever it is,
and do that in your hook.
I'll be honest with you.
I don't tell people this too often.
I'll be critiquing people's content in the
Discord, and someone will go, "James,
how's my reel?" And straight away,
I'll say, "Your hook
was terrible." They go,
"Okay, what about the rest?" I go,
"What do you mean the rest?
The hook was terrible. There is no rest.
No one made it there." So let's think of
an analogy off the top of my head.
You could use your iPhone to depict energy
balance.
You could say an iPhone has got a battery.
However,
if I do not charge it for the amount I use
it, the net amount of battery
will decrease over time.
Although I'm charging it on a regular
basis, if the amount
of charge going into the phone doesn't
match the amount being used,
there would be
a deficit in battery,
and you would expect to finish the day at
70, 50, or even
30%.
That is how fat loss works in the human
body.
Then as you're explaining energy balance
and calories, you would talk about that
charge versus usage ratio.
We could use the phone less, so it could
then find a positive balance to charge,
or we could charge the phone more,
whatever
it is. Then they go, "Oh,
do you know what?
Never thought of it like that." Another
thing, we were talking about macros,
right?
Something I always use with my clients
was, okay, protein remains the same.
Carbs and fats, what do they do?
Think of a hybrid, like a Toyota Prius.
It has an electric,
and it has a petrol motor.
The petrol motor is more so
when the electric can't keep up with it.
So if you jump on the motorway,
put your foot down,
the petrol motor kicks in.
But then at easier tasks,
maneuvering around the city,
the petrol motor shuts off
and you use electric.
Electric would represent fats,
petrol represent
carbohydrates. You tell someone that,
they go, "Do you know what, James?
I've heard that so many times over the
years in content.
That's the first time it's made sense."
Boosh.
Now, some people are going to say
are some niches more profitable than
others?
And yes and no,
but in the realm of fitness, right,
first of
all, muscle growth, don't go there.
Unless you're built like Chris Hemsworth
and you've got top-tier genetics, just
don't even go. It is a cesspit. It
is a shithole.
You've got Mike Israetel, Jeff Nippard,
all of these bros.
"Oh, yeah,
the muscle's not in the stretched
position, but the sarcasm isn't..."
Don't do it.
Save yourself the headaches because
if you're not in amazing shape,
you're just opening yourself up for attack
because people will, in muscle growth,
associate your credibility with the amount
of muscle that you have.
That doesn't even bring into the fray
things like steroids.
Fat loss,
as long as you're evidence-based, fine.
We have another realm maybe looking at
menopausal, perimenopausal women, and then
we have kind of the training. But
if you're going to talk about training,
don't
talk about muscle growth,
talk about performance,
talk about strength and
conditioning, talk about programming,
periodization, movements, all of those.
Just don't go into
that muscle growth sphere.
It's not worth it.
Now,
are some niches more profitable than
others?
I would say fat loss is the biggest one.
And again, you're like, "Oh,
but loads of people do it."
When it comes to fat loss,
there's something called the observer
effect.
If you watch someone do something,
they will do it better.
It's how micromanaging occurs.
You can also get the same.
If you lift weights,
I record my heavy sets. Do you know why?
Because I lift more,
because it's being recorded,
and I'm going to stick it on my
Instagram story.
I use the observer effect to hit more
fucking reps.
Some people, the observer effect
is the difference between them doing it
or not
doing it.
So you're not just selling fat loss,
you're selling the observation of
checking in, being on top of the client,
because that person is going to have a
calorie amount they need to hit. And
if you're observing them for 100 bucks a
week,
they're probably going to stick to it.
And if no one cares, they're probably not.
So when I say fat loss,
you're not selling a calorie deficit,
you're selling
accountability.
You're selling all of those components of
caring about that person.
Because in that person's life,
they probably don't have
that many people that give
a shit. Their partner, you might think,
yeah, sure, but the partner
often may have slipped down the same path
as the person you're working with, and
they become a saboteur.
Their husband starts getting in real good
shape, and the
wife's like, "Hey, babe,
do you want a bit of chocolate?" He's
like, "I'm on a
diet." She's like, "Oh,
I made dessert." And really,
she's just saboteuring his
efforts because if he gets fit
and she doesn't, it's going to alienate
her. The question there is,
do you even need to niche in fitness?
And some people do over-niche.
They're like,
"I do fat loss for mums." I go, "Okay,
why do you do fat loss for mums?" They
say, "Oh, they're women, they don't look
after themselves enough.
They don't get enough sleep." Well,
nurses could fit into
that. Some people are like, "Yeah,
I work with
corporate CEOs." I'm like, "Oh,
you want to work with rich people?
Why wouldn't you work with a bricklayer?
Because most bricklayers have got more
cash than most fucking corporate CEOs."
Just
don't over-niche. There
are some people online, "Hey, lesbians,
if you want to lose
weight," you're like, "Cool,
tell me about the energy balance equation
of mug
runting." I just don't get it.
I don't get it.
I'm sorry,
but licking the punani doesn't change fat
loss, in my opinion, until I
see a study to bloody say otherwise.
So when it comes to niching, those
are the main real considerations.
That's stage one. Done, dusted.
Let's move into stage two.
Do you need to be on all platforms? Ah.
If you're going to create a short-form
piece of content, think of it this way.
You're creating a digital asset
that you're going to float to the
internet, and
it's going to do some work for you.
Depending on how good that asset is,
depends on
how well it's going to perform.
If you put out a shit piece of content,
mm, do a
bit. But if you put some time, energy,
and effort into that piece of content, the
algorithm's going to work for you to put
it in front of people.
Now,
if you're going to create an Instagram
Reel, probably should go to TikTok,
probably throw it on LinkedIn,
put it to YouTube Shorts,
put it to Facebook. Why?
Why not? Oh,
but I don't really have an audience on
Facebook. Don't care.
Fucking put it there. On Instagram,
all you've got to do is push it through.
And if that's too much, there
are platforms out there
that post to social media for
you. But just going to remind you,
I am busier than you,
probably wealthier than
you, maybe more successful than you,
and I still post individually to all
platforms. Why? Because it matters.
30 years ago, you couldn't do this.
30 years ago, impossible. Right now,
I could put a video on a certain platform,
and
it changes my life. Don't sleep on that.
The only considerations
is the short-form content,
long-form content.
This right now is a long piece of content.
I spent years on short form.
I do prefer making longer form now,
but don't skip a step.
Actually, there's a video
that I've done recently
that explains why you need to
become a master in short form to then
become a master at long form.
Then you're probably thinking,
how often do I need to upload?
On short form, every day.
I'd say every day. Just getting it.
Think about all the bullshit you tell your
clients.
As a PT, you're like, "Yeah,
so I'm going to give you 10,000 steps a
day." Why?
Because 10,000? No,
because you just need a part of their
identity that they can
pay into every day. Because most,
even your fattest clients,
are only training
three, four times a week.
You need something for those other three
days.
You go, "Right, your new identity
is you now do 10,000 steps a day." It's
more
about the process of doing something every
day that pays into that identity.
I am here to lose weight. Same with you.
Post content every day.
Oh, I just don't know
if I can do content every day.
Well,
fuck off back to recruitment then
and do that for a fucking job because
you're doing my head in.
You're not even in my program yet.
Now,
I didn't say you need to create a fucking
Christopher Nolan every time you
post.
You could screenshot a tweet for all I
care, or do a carousel post with a few
photos. You could do September wrapped up.
I don't care.
It's more about the frequency of you
becoming a person feels like there's a bit
of
an itch that needs to be scratched
if you make it through the day without
posting
something. That's what I care about.
What's working at the moment? Well, Reels.
Don't think about you,
think about the platform.
Remember,
Instagram doesn't give a fuck about you.
It cares about itself.
And what does Instagram want?
For you to stay on the platform.
To get people to stay on the platform,
they need good content.
So they're going to show the best content
to keep people on the platform.
Most people brain rot scroll through
Reels.
So if you want to get in front of people,
put something out there as a Reel.
Not for you, but for them.
Millions of people looking for
entertainment, looking
for all of this kind of information,
Reels is going to be best.
Reels will get you in front of new people.
Carousel posts with the swiping photos,
great for an existing audience.
So I'd use Reels to grow.
I'd use carousels to tap into those
people, especially
with call to ways,
implementing things like chatbots.
Chatbots and Reels don't work so well,
but a carousel, people can go through the
story at their own pace,
and they can see and read the call to
action, and if you
find it irresistible, they will do it.
Written posts. I love a good written post.
I would float it out on LinkedIn,
post it on Twitter, then if it does well,
chuck
an image with it,
stick it on your [chuckles] YouTube
community wall, maybe even
stick it on Instagram. Ultimately,
over time, through doing different,
we call them
campaigns in marketing.
We do some written post campaigns,
do some video campaigns,
then you can see what's working for your
business.
If you have an email marketing platform,
which you should, which is a whole video
altogether, you will see the peaks
and troughs and spikes of people signing
up to
your email list. And if it is very,
very high on a day you do a carousel, you
repeat what works. Again,
when I look at people's content,
whether YouTube or
Instagram or whatever,
I go through to look at what performed
really well.
I will find it. I'll go, "Hey, Dave,
you said you're struggling to grow your
audience." "Yep." "Three weeks ago,
you made this Reel, which
is different to all
your other Reels,
and it got 10 times more views." "Yeah."
"How many times have you
remade that piece of content that
was an outlier?" "Uh,
I haven't." "What the fuck, Dave? Come on,
remake that.
Let's copy the hook, the style, the topic.
Let's make several videos.
Let's see which one performs better out of
that so we can know. Was it the hook?
Was it the style? Was it the context?"
Are subscribers and followers even that
important in the modern day? Yeah,
for vanity. That's it.
You look at this YouTube, you're like,
"Dude's got nearly 50,000 subs.
He's probably legit." Well,
got 460-odd thousand on that
channel, and then I've got a podcast with,
like, 50-odd thousand as well.
It's quite good for a dick-measuring
contest, but not really,
because ultimately,
the most important thing is
that people watch your content
and vibe with it.
70% of people on this channel
are not subscribed when they watch,
and I don't care.
Here's the thing as well.
You can watch all my videos for ten years.
I never ask for a follow,
and I never ask you to subscribe.
Some people on the channel are like, "Hey,
guys, don't forget to like and
subscribe.
Tap that like" Desperate fucking beggy
beta
male bullshit. If you like my shit,
you can watch it, and if you want
to subscribe so you don't miss out, cool.
But I'm not going to sit here
and beg you for it.
My marketing style is, here it is.
Take it if you want it.
Same reason I don't do sales calls,
which we'll get into in a second.
Imagine there's 100 people
that want to do business with me.
30 of them get to the landing page, go,
"Sweet, I'm in." Then there are another 30
people that would join
if they need a sales call.
I'd rather not have their money.
It's a pride thing for me.
I'm not getting on the phone
and begging you to fucking
give me your money.
It's pathetic I would rather just have
less money.
I'd rather live in a smaller house.
And for you,
you should have a similar marketing
approach.
You shouldn't be using ManyChats
or auto DM people when they follow you.
Do you know how desperate that looks?
No millionaire...
Actually,
there's some desperate millionaires.
I've seen them.
Have a bit of personal pride to your
business.
marketing.
Some of you are 35-year-olds,
you've got kids,
and you're begging strangers
on the internet to follow you.
Do you know how pathetic that is?
I'm sorry, but it is. Hey, and
if you followed me, you'd know that. Stop.
No one is getting highly paid begging for
followers.
So you're probably thinking at this stage,
if the subscribers aren't important,
should I be replying
and responding to DMs and comments?
If you're a small account,
respond to comments, respond to DMs.
Absolutely.
As you get bigger, if you want.
Ultimately, it's better that
if people want to have
a discourse with you, sure,
open up your email inbox, say to people,
"Hey,
respond here." Now,
when you're a little bit bigger
or in a position that I am, a
legend, people will send me a long email,
and a lot of the time, they're just
looking for reassurance.
Will I get them on a sales call? No.
I'll just say, "Hey, look,
if you don't love it,
let me know within a few months.
I'll refund you in full."
That means I've just serviced someone in
11 seconds,
which some of you
are spending an hour on the call with.
And again,
another thing you fucking PTs are doing,
you're sat at home going,
"Oh, I've got client check-ins today.
Oh, I've got five client check-ins.
We've got a call." Has it ever occurred to
you that your fucking clients don't like
the check-ins either?
If some of you have got 15,
20 online clients, let's say.
Message them all,
"I'm not doing check-ins anymore.
Instead,
I'm replacing it with a WhatsApp number
that you can just message whenever
you need anything." 80% of them
are going to go, "Fucking hell.
Thank God." 20% are like, "Oh,
I really like the check-ins, though.
They're crucial for me." Keep that 20%.
You're now doing 80% less calls a week.
I had PT clients back in the day.
I was like, "Look, do you mind
if we made the session 45 minutes?" They
go, "That's
better for me,
actually." No change in price.
All I had to do was ask.
So DMs, comments, kind of responding here,
maybe a little bit spend on it.
Subscribers, followers, important.
The next question you're probably thinking
is: how do I get loyal followers that
want to work with me?
How do you stand out?
How do you build that rapport?
Well, you get in front of them,
and you turn up, and you put out videos.
Today, it's 33 degrees in Sydney.
It's beautiful weather. It's Sunday.
But I'm here getting your business. Why?
Because it's important.
It's important that we have a little
relationship going on right now.
We've got a little dance.
And my competitors
are doing the dance with you as well.
But I'm going to outwork them.
I'm going to out-angle them.
I don't script my videos.
If you go watch any of the competitors
that I
have, watch their videos.
They're reading a script.
They didn't even write the script.
The biggest guys in this field have three
to five writers that work full
time scripting shit.
They're just a bit of a puppet.
It's like, "Mah, mah, mah, mah,
mah." Some of them are quite good,
to be honest.
Their writers are amazing.
Does this seem scripted to you?
So for me, I'm in this dance with you.
I'm here to try and win your business.
And I'm not going to do it through sneaky
sales tactics.
I'm going to do it by wearing you the fuck
down.
When you decide to do business with me,
your reaction's going to be like, "All
right. Fucking hell. Let's do it.
All right, James. Took you 10 months.
I'm in." Cool.
That's how I like to market.
You should do the same with yours.
To the point they go, "Do you know what?
Fine. Let's do the PT consult.
Fine,
I'll do your online coaching." Wear people
down.
But wear them down in a way that's not
annoying.
Wear them down in a way
that every single bit of wear
and tear on the way there,
they learnt something.
They got benefit from it.
They got value from you.
And when you're giving value,
think about this.
Something that's really important
is having a good hook in content.
The hook that you have at the beginning of
the content is the thing that you do to
set up. If someone listens to your hook,
they should know what it's about, what
they can get, and whether
or not they need to stay.
Your hook isn't just to lure people in.
It's also to give people permission to
leave.
Your hook could be something,
"I ate eggs on toast for 32 days in a
row to prove strangers on the internet
wrong about fat loss." People that care
about fat loss go, "Cool.
I'm in." People that don't care are like,
"No.
Not bothered." But if you did a hook like,
"I did something for 32 days that would
confuse the internet, and by doing this,
it made a paradoxical equation that
could only be surmounted by doing..."
People there are like, "Oh." They're just
going to leave.
You need to give them some kind of
context.
Your hook can be a statement hook.
"People are wrong about this." It could be
a
question hook. "Did you know
that people used to think this?" It could
be a visual hook. "This
is a can of Nutric.
And this makes people very rich." Not you,
me.
Made me very rich. There
are loads of different hooks,
but the hook is the first
thing you say in content. It
is so important.
Again,
what I said about content critiquing.
People go,
"What about the rest of the reel?"
If the hook wasn't right, no one's
there, brother.
And those of you probably scripting out
some hooks right now,
you're probably thinking,
what equipment is necessary?
I built a million-dollar-a-year business
just using my phone.
Put it on a little tripod, went live,
gave people a link to join my email list,
sent them emails, sold memberships.
That was it.
Now, obviously, I've got the studio
and this. I only have this because I can.
You don't need any of this.
You don't need an invisible microphone.
Does that occur to you? Where's the mic?
Where is it? Is it here?
No. Is it here? [knocking] No.
It's hidden, brother.
Using a Sennheiser MKH 417.
Goes into the XLR cable in the FX3 for
any of you that are wondering. And yes,
it's 50 mil.
And I will be adding an ND filter to it
shortly, just in case any of you were
thinking that. Oh, what's that? My autism.
Don't worry about it.
So when it comes to equipment,
just have good audio, have a good video.
I used to do lives on a balcony in the sun
every morning. It was fine.
iPhone was fine. But
when you can afford to upgrade your
equipment, do it, because
some people care.
So that's probably enough of stage two.
Let's look into stage three quickly.
Once you've got a following,
once you've accrued followers, there
are things we
need to do to own those
and really to get them into the ecosystem,
to part of your
cult. We need lead magnets.
So I have one here on my desk from another
video that I
was filming. So for instance,
we can just say, "Hey,
if you want to get more
conversions from the exact same amount of
work that you're doing, download this."
There'll probably be a link in the
description for that.
Now,
some of my traffic goes to people going to
my webpage.
They just want to find out how much it
is to work with me.
I don't expect those to convert too much.
You'll see the links in the description.
Most things I do is to get people's email
addresses. Let me tell you why.
About six months ago, I did a live stream,
and it was about content, and during the
live stream, the stream kicked out.
It just kaput. YouTube gone.
Whatever. Now, for most people,
that would've been an absolute nightmare,
but for
me,
it was fine because I had 1,200 people
that signed up and gave me their email
address. I emailed them all,
and I apologized, said,
"Sorry about the live stream
kicking out.
Here's an offer." Sent them the offer,
did about $12,000 in sales.
Now, if I had not got the email first,
it would've been a catastrophe.
But because I had the emails,
I got to go to bed 45 minutes early.
It was fine.
You need emails.
That's how you communicate with people.
That's how you can take them away from
social media.
Because even right now,
you're watching this on YouTube.
You might be driving your car, not here,
or you might be chopping onions in the
kitchen making dinner.
You might be doing whatever,
iPad to the side while you're
doing work. I don't mind.
But I eventually want to get you away from
this platform
because even probably down the sidebar
here, for those of you psychopaths
that are
watching it on a laptop,
there's going to be loads of my
competitors here, all
wanting your attention,
all wanting your money.
So me getting an email
and taking you away means I can have a
communication with
you. I, in fact,
wrote an email this morning telling
everyone I'm about to double
my prices in the new year. Why?
Because I can. I'm busy.
The reason I'm recording this at 2:00 PM
is because I had to spend the morning in
the bloody Discord. I'm busy.
And there's another one for you.
When you're too busy, pricing goes up.
We'll probably get into
that into the fourth part of the video.
Now, once I get your email address,
I will broadcast to you, and you should
broadcast to people. Just say, "Hey,
watched this film last night. It
was terrible.
It was terrible for these reasons.
Now thinking about that,
the only thing worse than
that film would be not to join
my program," have a bit of fun with it.
But you can create nurture sequences
and automations.
For instance, you could,
I'll pin a comment on this video.
If I've forgotten, let me know.
How to run a better personal training
business in
30 days. Once you sign up,
I will automate the email
that goes to you, one every
day for 30 days, and then come day 19,
most people buy. Why? Don't know.
But that is an automation. So
if we set up automations to nurture
people, all we've
got to do is work hard on socials to get
them to sign up.
Once they sign up, everything else
is automated.
Someone will fist bump you in the street,
go, "Mate, today's email, fucking
awesome." And then you'll be like,
"I haven't sent an email in three months."
Automations, nurturing, unreal.
And my golden rule to depress you is this:
20% of your total audience should be
on your email list.
If you've got 1,000 followers
and you don't have 200 people on
your email list, you fucked up, brother.
You fucked up.
And you should 100% be having that.
Otherwise, come on.
20% or bust. That's what you need. Now,
for some of you that might be getting a
bit
overwhelmed at this part in the video,
just want to remind you,
there's actually a
quiz that I put in the description below.
If you do that,
you can get a bespoke answer to where you
should be putting your
focus. Is it the email list?
Is it the hooks? Is it the content?
Any of those things. Please do that quiz.
It could be very insightful for you.
Step number four, scaling.
How do you make money out of followers?
Well, you don't.
Followers will never pay you.
Clients will.
What you want to do
is you want to see those 100 followers
and get the email
addresses of 20 of them.
Out of those 20 people, maybe one or two,
maybe three
could become a client.
That's the way it works.
So if you need to double your clients,
you need to double the amount of people on
your email list. To do that,
you might need to double the amount of
followers you
have or double the amount of campaigns
that you're running to get people's email
addresses. Now,
a lot of you probably thinking,
do I work with people one-on-one?
Yes, to begin with. Group coaching?
Absolutely.
But just don't fall into the trap
that some of you charge a certain amount
for
coaching, and you want more money.
And you think, "Oh,
it's just a bit hard to get more people
onto the one-to-one."
So you drop your pants. You're like,
"I'm just going to do something cheap."
And
the problem is, it's not
that you're too expensive, it's
that not enough people
know or care about your services.
So although it can seem like a very
tempting
thing to just,
"I'm going to just do a cheap group
coaching program," instead, you
could just become better at turning up on
social media, better at getting people's
email addresses,
and better at nurturing those people.
And then your landing page has to have a
better offer that is clear and precise and
not overwhelming,
and a better money-back guarantee.
Because at the moment, most people
that buy your stuff,
they have to take all of
the risk because chances
are you could be shit.
I say that because about 20% of personal
trainers are fucking idiots.
So if you can take some of
that risk onto yourself, then it'll work.
For instance, NooTonic. So any of you
that ever buy this or try
this,
USA, UK mainly. Australia,
we've got the creatine,
but we'll be out soon.
If you didn't love that or any of them,
whatever you buy, you email me,
james@nootonic.com. Say, "Hey, mate,
I didn't like the citrus." Cool.
I'll refund you in full. Why?
Because now me giving you
that offer means I can take
all the risk so that you have to go buy
NooTonic now, or you're an idiot because
it's amazing.
You're either going to love it,
that it's worth the money, or you're
going to get your money back.
I'm not even doing
that because I like you.
I'm doing that so I can take the risk from
you, wear it myself, not just
because I'm rich, but because
if I take that risk,
you're going to end up
purchasing.
And everything I should do should be
getting people to purchase because
that offer just there could five-fold the
amount of people buying NooTonic from
this video. And even
if 1% to 5% of people end up getting a
refund, we're
in a much better net benefit position.
55% of people that buy NooTonic buy it
again within a month.
So even if it was 40% of people
that wanted a refund,
we would see our money back
probably in the third or fourth month.
What should you be charging?
Now, it's not the area you live in.
It's not economics.
It's not Zach Polanski
and the fucking Greens Party.
It's how many people want to do business
with you.
The reason I'm doubling my rates for my
mentorship in the new year is I am too
busy. There are too many people
that want to work with me, so I can.
For you,
you should have a set amount of hours
or a set amount of online PT
coaching slots. When they're full,
put up your rates.
If you're never full,
you could be too expensive.
Drop your rates, get full,
then increase your rates.
It's a sliding scale, like plane seats.
When you sit on a plane,
if it's school holidays, you pay more.
Why?
Because more people want the seats.
It's a basic commodity. Demand.
Typically, online coaching,
your weekly rate should be in line with
your hourly
rate. Again, but if your online's full,
put the rates up.
If your in-person's full,
And then if you've got a few hours free in
the diary because a few people drop off
because you put your rates up,
market more, make more content,
put out more offers,
send more emails. Then you get full again,
then you put up your rates and
My mentorship, when it started,
was like 700 US dollars.
It's about to go to five grand.
What happened? I just got busier.
That's it.
5K is still steel.
I know what you're thinking.
Now, the rough timeline of making money
is the tough part we've got to talk about
now. Now, online's great,
but building an online business,
three to six months.
Most people in my mentorship will not get
a full diary with less than three months.
So you need to have
that in-person part of the business
because to go out and win
money next week, online, difficult,
in-person, easy.
And you want to have an in-person business
that pays your bills.
Even if it's just covering your rent,
covering your mortgage,
covering your food,
sweet, the online can be the stuff
that you build into.
But you can't just quit your job in
recruitment and go all in online because
you
might be three to six months.
You're planting seeds now
that might take a long time
to harvest.
So if you're not willing to work on the
gym floor because you think
you're too good of a coach,
or you think you're too important,
or you think your
skills are too good,
or you think you used to PT people five
years ago, fuck off.
How about have a bit of humble pie,
you fucking prick?
Go do the hours because those hours,
although they might not be paid, and yes,
you've got to get it up, and yes,
you've got to go to a gym, and yes,
you've got to
pay rent. These fucking people here
are going to teach you so much about how
you
get the online clients.
The only reason that I dominated in online
is because the
amount of people that I coached in person.
I know people, I know their problems,
I know the issues they're having,
I know the
insecurities they're having.
I know what they think about their
husband.
I know how happy their words go to the
school play today.
I know everything about them. It
is the thousands of shitty paid hours
that I did
here that made me the millions here.
And if you think you can skip that step,
fuck you. You can't. You're not that good.
And you're not even that good a coach.
And you could even be an amazing coach,
but if you don't understand the people,
you
can never communicate with them.
And remember,
if I wanted to be a real prick, if I
really wanted to be an asshole in this
video, I'd go, "Yeah,
just join my program,
and you'll get loads of clients in the
first two months." I'm being real.
This is how it fucking works.
Welcome to the layer cake, son.
If you're not going to give me three to
six months to build your online client
base
to 10 clients, you are fucking dreaming.
Because we've got to get you good at
content. That's going to take a while.
Then we've got to get you comfortable in
front of camera.
Then we've got to get you good at hooks.
We've got to get you to eat so much
fucking shit before your content even
takes
off,
let alone people reacting to your fucking
call to actions to get their email
address.
Then your email's going to be shit.
Then you've got the reputation,
you've got the domains,
you've got all the issues
we have with email marketing.
And keep in mind,
most of my competitors tell you,
"Send 100 DMs a day
and do sales calls" because this shit
is fucking hard and it
takes time. And if you
were wanting to DM strangers
and do sales call, fuck off to
someone else's course because that's not
what I do. I'm not a beggy cunt, remember?
So we've got all of this shit here.
Then the landing page.
If you're a dude,
it's going to look like shit.
Women can create a nice landing page. Men,
awful.
They use colors like bright orange,
Kawasaki green, and red.
Red on a landing page.
Yes for your button to buy now.
Fucking off for everything else.
You dudes, I wonder how you fucking dress
yourselves with landing pages like that.
So this takes fucking time.
If you're not willing to suck for a few
months, no offense, you're just not going
to make it and you should go back to
recruitment.
So the timeline of making money,
in person, we can get crooking right away,
and
that alleviates the stress. So
when you're online,
you're a bit more carefree.
There's nothing worse than desperation.
And you can see the online coaches like,
"Join my program. Join my program.
Join my program." Desperation, gone.
And some of you are thinking like Circle,
WAP, School, all of that.
Look,
I've never seen anything really slap.
I don't know anyone who's comfortably
making 100K a month,
killing it in the online
coaching space, and they're like,
"I use School." I think School,
no offense, my
personal opinion,
is just a place for Alex Hormozi bum boys.
If there are some people
that wake up at 4:00 a.m.
just to wank Hormozi off onto their face,
and they're like, "I love School.
I love School." And the fact Eddie Abu
uses it is enough.
I've had two cans of Noatonic.
I've raw dogged this whole video.
How long have we been going for? 20 or 22.
Fuck, that's the fucking time.
I don't even know how long we've been
going for. So that was scaling.
Last thing we need to talk about,
probably mindset.
What to do if your posts
are stuck on 150 views a video?
Make them better.
Make them better. Better thought-out hook.
If you're in my Discord,
give me your hook.
Let me tear it to shreds.
Post about things more important,
more interesting. Use products.
You can even do a fitness video. Why
is everyone obsessed about Noatonic,
and do
these ingredients actually benefit you,
or is this a scam?
Better yet,
is James Smith ripping people off
and scamming them with his new
product called Noatonic?
Let's look into it. Again,
another banging hook.
Because then you could tap into some pop
culture.
People are getting served our adverts
or whatever they've heard about the drink.
They want to know the answer. Boom,
you're in.
You're going to get more than 150 views
for that.
And these are the biggest mistakes I see
in the mentorship. Imagine this.
This is the easiest way I could explain
it.
Imagine you and I
are working together on a fucking
10-minute video for YouTube,
and it's really, really fucking important.
And we have editors and we hire them.
You might go, "Right, guys,
10-minute video, 10 hours to edit.
One hour per minute." No.
Let's take five hours of editors' time for
that
first one minute because
that first one minute
is where people decide whether they
stay or they go.
Then they can do the next nine minutes in
the fucking five hours
that's left.
That is the way we need to approach
content.
You have this much effort for this much of
video.
Take that much effort and put it into
that first part of the video.
There are going to be a lot of emotional
ups and downs. This video could bomb.
If this video doesn't do 10K,
I'll be livid.
But that's fine because I will use
that anger and sadness
and depression to get
myself into tomorrow's video
and the next day's video.
Or it can make me loads of money
and I'll be equally numb
and think to myself,
"It's not enough."
But the only thing I can say
is to fall in love with the
process.
I enjoy making videos more than I enjoy
making money.
And it's a good job the videos make money
because otherwise I'll be fucked.
But the one thing I want to close out on
in this, all the things I've told you
today about getting good at content,
landing pages, email marketing,
all of that.
If you had come up to me eight years ago
and gone, "James, you know you've got an
in-person PT business.
Soon you're going to have an online
business that makes
millions." Wouldn't have believed you.
If you then said two years later, "Oh,
you're going to have a book that's going
to
be a 'Sunday Times' number one bestseller,
and you're going to do it three times."
Wouldn't have believed you.
If you then said, "Oh,
you're going to have a million
followers on social media." Wouldn't have
believed you.
If you then said,
"You're going to scale a productivity
drink and a nootropics
business to 20 million in two years." I
wouldn't have believed you.
And if you said that you
were running a business mentorship
that does several
million US dollars a year,
I wouldn't have believed you.
Personal brand only makes sense looking
backwards.
And for a lot of you,
although you're in the fitness industry
now, this is not
where you're going to finish.
If you can get good at all of these things
that I
conveniently teach people for money,
links in the description.
If you can get good at this, this
is where it begins.
A fitness business
is where many entrepreneurs start.
Look at Alex Hormozi.
If you can become a weapon in fitness,
everything else is easy.
Because let's be honest,
we sell fucking workouts
and we tell people to eat less.
It's the shittiest thing to sell in the
world.
This is an energy drink
that tastes better than all the
competitors and has more
and does more. That's easy to sell.
So if you can put your eggs in your basket
and conquer and dedicate
yourself to building a personal brand in
the fitness industry in the next three to
five years,
whatever you put your attention to after
is easy.
Sorry to be big-headed.
The reason I'm so good at this
and communicating is I did
5,000 hours of chatting shit on the gym
floor, talking to my clients.
Do you know how easy it
is to talk to a camera in an
air-conditioned room, sat down
at a desk when you've just spent fucking
five years of your life working
with people one-to-one for seven hours a
day?
So please check out the links in the
description. Buy shit from it.
And again, like I said,
jamesandnootonic.com.
If there's something wrong,
you think I've underdelivered on my
promise, just email
me. Buy Nootonic, just email me. And
if you're still not convinced at the end
of
this video that I'm the person to help you
with your personal brand in the fitness
industry going into 2026, that's fine.
I hope you enjoy recruitment,
but even more,
you might enjoy this video here that
I've put here for you.
Thank you very much for tuning in.
Bye-bye.